Guide to the North Carolina Council of Churches records, 1935-2019 RL.00934
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (2001-0100)
  - Wake County Mental Health, Mrs. Marilyn Chabot (Box 80)
  - Warren County (Box 80)
  - Wayne County/Goldsboro, Possible urban site (Box 80)
  - Vintage, 2 folders (Box 80)
  - Visitation Programs, 3 folders (Box 80)
  - Telephone Reassurance Programs [for the elderly], ca. 1975, 55 folders (Box 80)
  - Meals On Wheels Programs, 4 folders (Box 80)
  - Communities, 2 folders (Box 81)
  - Church Women United, 1970-1975, 17 folders (Box 81)
  - Model Projects, 1975-1976, 8 folders (Box 82)
  - United Methodist Churches, 1975, 5 folders (Box 82)
  - NCCC Miscellaneous, A-Y, [Samuel Wilkins, Executive Director] 1965-1978 (Box 82)
    Includes Advisory Conference, 1972; Camping, 1964-1968; Recreation Committee, 1967-1974; Boy Scouts, 1971-1978; and Youth, 1969.
  - NCCC Miscellaneous, A-Y, continued, 8 folders (Box 83)
  - Seminar on Church and Community; Communication Awards; and Annual Meetings, 1964-1972, 24 folders (Box 83)
    Includes primarily Annual meeting and Pastors' Conference materials.
  - Scrapbook/Binder, NCCC, 1958-1961 (Box 83)
  - Scrapbooks/binders, 1942-1968, 27 folders (Box 84)
    Includes United Church Women materials, 1953-1968, and Weekday Religious Education materials, 1946-1951.
  - NCCC Denominations (Morton Kurtz, Executive Secretary), 1941-1960, 51 folders (Box 85)
    Includes Methodist A.M.E. Zion, Baptist, Congregational, Disciples of Christ, and Episcopal.
  - NCCC Denominations, continued (Box 86)
    Includes Methodist and Presbyterian.
  - Materials on aging compiled by the Rev. Richard F. McCleary, Model Project Ministries with Aging, 1974-1975, 4 folders (Box 86)
    Contains mostly printed material.
  - Materials on aging, continued., 25 folders (Box 87)
  - Personnel files, 1953-1969
    - CROP-Personnel, 1955-1959,from box that contained Ministry for Overseas Relief materials (Box 87)
    - Staff, 1953-1963 (Box 87)
    - Prospective Teachers, 1953-1959,from box that contained UCW Weekday Religious Education material (Box 87)
  - Publications by the NCCC or compiled by NCCC staff, ca. 1933-1960, 9 folders (Box 88)
    Includes the Church Council Bulletin, 1940-1949 and publications on migrants.
  - Publications by the NCCC or compiled by NCCC staff, continued, 9 folders (Box 89)
    Includes publications on migrants and material for council scrapbook.
  - Publications by the NCCC or compiled by NCCC staff, continued, 9 folders (Box 90)
  - Weekday Religious Education, 1930-1955,[continued from box 93]
    - Teachers, U-Z (Box 90)
    - Theses [on religious instruction], 7 folders (Box 90)
  - Rural Church Publications, 1944-1955 (Box 91)
  - Washington Newsletter, FCNL, 1952-1954 (Box 91)
  - First Convocation, Winston-Salem, 1936 October 26-1936 October 28 (Box 91)
  - NC United Christian Youth Movement, 1952-1959, 25 folders (Box 91)
    Includes training conference and spring and fall council meeting materials as well as photographs.
  - NCCC General Council and Annual meetings, 1955-1963, 11 folders (Box 91)
  - Biographies, 1961-1962 (Box 91)
  - NC Council Bulletin, 1951-1963, 2 folders (Box 91)
  - Christian Social Action Commission, 1962-1963 (Box 91)
  - Christian Social Action Director, 1963 (Box 92)
  - Christmas Letters (Morton Kurtz), 1955-1962 (Box 92)
  - "Civil Defense" (Box 92)
  - College Work Committee (Box 92)
  - Councils-Suggestions for Activities of (Box 92)
  - General: Directory of Churches, 1954-1963 (Box 92)
  - Ecumenical Voluntary Service Projects (including applications for summer work camps) (Box 92)
  - Responses to Editorial, 1959 (Box 92)
  - Finance Board, 3 folders (Box 92)
  - Foundations (Box 92)
  - Governor's Committee on Aging (Box 92)
  - Billy Graham Crusade (Box 92)
  - Information Requests, 1959, 2 folders (Box 92)
  - Governor's Committee on Juvenile Delinquency (Box 92)
  - General: Kiwanis Clubs (Box 92)
  - General: Social Welfare (Box 92)
  - Peace Action (Box 92)
  - General: Protestants and other Americans United (Box 92)
  - MRK-Library (Box 92)
  - National Conference Christians and Jews (Box 92)
  - NC Council on Human Relations (Box 92)
  - General: Kurtz-Officers, Correspondence With (Box 92)
  - MRK: General Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 92)
  - Literature (Box 92)
  - Local Councils (Box 92)
  - Ministerial Associations, 1960-1961 (Box 92)
  - Mailing List (Box 92)
  - Mental Health (Box 92)
  - National Service Corp (Box 92)
  - Office for Councils of Churches, National Council of Churches (Box 92)
  - Southeastern Advisory Committee (Box 92)
  - Tercentenary Commission (Box 92)
  - Dr. Samuel S. Wiley, Director (Box 92)
  - United Nations (Box 92)
  - World Council (Box 92)
  - Revised Standard Version Bible Observance (RSVBO), 1951-1953, 48 folders (Box 93)
  - Personnel files
    - Migrant Personnel, 1959-1963,from box that contained Migrant Work UCW Denominations 1960 (Box 93)
    - Jack Crum, 1968-1977 (Box 93)
    - Personnel Committee, 1968,from box that contained General Correspondence and Financial (Box 93)
  - Weekday Religious Education, Teachers and Theses, 1945-1963 (Box 93)
  - Informer General Information [from box 70] (Box 94)
  - [Loose materials], [including from box 87], 4 folders (Box 94)
  - [Migrant Project] and Migrant Ministry, 1963-1965, 3 folders (Box 94)
  - United Church Women, 1960, 2 folders (Box 94)
  - Bulletin, 1960 (Box 94)
  - North Carolina Council of Churches, 1969-1970 (Box 94)
  - Morton R. Kurtz Travel Expenses, 1956-1961 (Box 94)
  - North Carolina Sunday School Association, Report on Audit, 1928-1929 (Box 94)
  - [Receipts, Disbursements], [bound volume], 1933-1937 (Box 94)
  - Henricksen, G. C., Durham Council of Churches, 1947-1949 (Box 94)
  - Durham Council of Churches, 1942-1948, 2 folders (Box 94)
  - Minutes of the board of Managers-Department of United Church Women of the NCCC, 1963 (Box 94)
  - Mr. Samuel S. Wiley, 1941-1948 (Box 94)
    Budget and finances.
  - Scrapbook/binders [from box 84]
    - 1949-1950 (Box 94)
    - Christian Rural Fellowship Bulletins, 1949-1951 (Box 94)
  - RSVBO: General Information [from box 93] (Box 94)
  - Address cards, ca. 1939-1942 (Box 95)
    Includes notes by archivist.
  - Address and meeting registration cards (Box 96)
    Also includes a [newspaper printer's block]: photo of "Wiley."
  - United Church Women Scrapbook, 1955-1956 and loose material from elsewhere in the collection (Box 97)
- Accession (2001-0135)
  - Subject/Office Files, A-C, 1969-1971, 16 folders (Box 1)
    Includes Abortion 1970-1971; Calendar, 1969-1970.
  - Correspondence, 1970-1971, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Appointment Schedule/Daily Log, 1969-1970, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Subject/Office Files E-L, 1969-1971, 12 folders (Box 1)
  - Subject/Office Files, L-Z, 1969-1971, 40 folders (Box 2)
    Includes Prison Ministries, 1970
  - Incoming letters, 1978, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Criminal Justice, 1978-1979, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Legislative Affairs, 1978, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Subject/Office Files, M-W, 1978-1979, 11 folders (Box 2)
    Includes Wilmington 10 Task Group, 1978; ERA Committee, 1977-1979.
  - State Human Resources, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Equal Rights Ammendment, 1977-1979, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Food Stamps, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
  - Soul City, NC, 1974, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Collins Kilburn Director of Social Ministries NCCC, 1974, 13 folders (Box 3)
  - Calendar, Collins Kilburn, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports, [1972-1974], 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Subject/Office Files, A-N, [1969-1974], 65 folders (Box 3)
    Includes Committee on Government and Legislation, 1974.
  - Subject/Office Files, L-Z, 1973-1974, 33 folders (Box 4)
  - Press Release and Publicity, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Ideas-Planning Long Range, 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Legislative Affairs, 1972-1977, 12 folders (Box 4)
  - Resolutions, N.C. Council of Ch., 1973, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Prison Reform, 1976, 6 folders (Box 4)
  - Hunger, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Finances, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, Collins Kilburn Director of Social Ministries NCCC, 1975, 12 folders (Box 5)
  - Kilburn Subject/Office files A-W, 1975, 102 folders (Box 5)
    Includes an NCCC annual report for 1974-1975; calendar, 1975; office accounts, 1970-1972; and State Council for Social Legislation material, 1975-1976 (16 folders)
  - Correspondence, Collins Kilburn Director of Social Ministries NCCC, 1979 January-1979 March, 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, Collins Kilburn Director of Social Ministries NCCC, 1979 April-1979 December, 9 folders (Box 6)
  - Kilburn Subject/Office files, A-R, 1979, 97 folders (Box 6)
    Includes Commission on Christian Social Ministries material, 1979; Social Committee for ERA material, 1979; NCCC Executive Board meetings, 1978-1979; Labor-Management Committee material, 1979; and Refugee Resettlement Committee, 1979.
  - Kilburn Subject/Office files, R-W, 1979, 12 folders (Box 7)
    Includes continuation of Refugee Resettlement Committee, 1979.
  - Welfare Reform, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Migrants-National, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Prison Reform and Construction, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Reports by Collins Kilburn, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Public Schools, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Senior Citizens Conference, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Social Security, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Subject/Office Files, A-E, 1977-1980, 9 folders (Box 8)
    Includes Criminal Justice Committee, 1978; Committee on ERA, 1978; Labor-Management Committee, 1978; Migrant Ministry.
  - Correspondence, 1978, 12 folders (Box 8)
  - Subject/Office Files, A-Z, 1978, 73 folders (Box 8)
  - Planning-Finance, 1978 (Box 9)
  - North Carolinians for Tax Reform, 1975, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - ERA United, [1977-1979], 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Hunt Committee-Crime Prevention, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Incoming letters, 1979, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Incoming letters, 1976 July-Dec., 2 folders (Box 9)
  - General Assembly Bills/Incoming letters, 1977, 10 folders (Box 9)
  - NCCC Interns, 1975, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - NCCC Annual Assembly, 19976,1977 (Box 9)
  - NCCC Executive Board, 1975-1977 (Box 9)
  - Commission on Social Ministries, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Gay Churches, 19777 (Box 9)
  - Humanities Committee, 1977 (Box 9)
  - Humphry-Hawkin, 1978 (Box 9)
  - Mail, 1979 Aug.-Dec., 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Incoming letters, 1977, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Migrant Farm Workers, 1977, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1982, 12 folders (Box 10)
  - Subject/Office Files, A-F, 1982, 43 folders (Box 10)
    Includes Commission on Christian Nurture, 1982; Commission on Christian Unity, 1982; ERA Committee, 1982; Executive Board, 1982; Finance, 1982; Church Council Bulletin, 1982.
  - Appointment Book, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Welfare Reform, 1977 (Box 10)
  - WHEAT, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Pornography, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Prison Reform, 1977, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Occupational Safety, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Older Adults, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Tax Reform, 1977, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Urban Policy, 1978 (Box 10)
  - Subject/Office Files, C-Z, 1970-1984, 66 folders (Box 11)
    Includes House of Delegates, 1984; Church and State Task Group, 1970; Welfare and Human Rights, 1970.
  - correspondence, H-R, 1976, 12 folders (Box 11)
  - Incoming letters, 1980 January-1980 August, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Divorce Bill, 1980, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Incoming letters, 1983, 6 folder (Box 12)
  - Incoming letters, 1981, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Incoming letters, 1982, 5 folders (Box 12)
  - Incoming letters, 1984, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Incoming letters, 1987, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Subject/Office Files, H-Z, 1981, 54 folder (Box 13)
    Includes House of Delegates, 1981; Migrant Ministry and Housing, 1981; Peace Committee, 1981.
  - Subject/Office Files, C-P, 1986, 60 folders (Box 13)
    Includes Committee on Christian Social Ministries, 1986; Committee on Church and Public Education, 1986; Criminal Justice Committee, 1986; ERA Committee, 1986; Executive Board, 1986; Migrant Ministry, 1986; Peace and Security Committee, 1986.
  - Appointment Book, 1983 (Box 14)
  - Outgoing Mail Log, 1982 Sep. - 1983 Sep. (Box 14)
  - Telephone Message Log, 1982 May 26 - 1984 Jan. 10, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1983, 12 folders (Box 14)
  - Subject/Office Files, A-C, [1981-1983], 43 folders (Box 14)
    Includes Central America Materials, 1982-1983; Committee on Social Ministries; Church Council Bulletin, 1983; Communications Committee, 1983; Criminal Justice, 1980.
  - Subject/Office Files, C-H, 1982, 24 folders (Box 15)
    Includes Criminal Justice, 1982-1983; ERA Committee and Committee on Women's Issues, 1983; House of Delegates and Executive Board Meeting, 1983.
  - Correspondence, 1977, 13 folder (Box 15)
  - Calendar, 1977 (Box 15)
  - Subject/Office Files, A-W, 1977, 60 folders (Box 15)
    Includes Wilmington 10, 1977.
  - Local Ecumenical Soc. Service, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Caring Program for Children, 1986, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Presbyterians, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Farm Crisis, 1986, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, 1988, 12 folders (Box 16)
  - Subject/Office Files, A-U, 1988, 25 folders (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 1993, 18 folders (Box 17)
  - House of Delegates, 1993 (Box 17)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1993 (Box 17)
  - Fax Messages, 1993 (Box 17)
  - N.C. For Gun Control, 1993 (Box 17)
  - House of Delegates, 1993, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - NCCC Nominating Committee Meeting, 1993 (Box 17)
  - Distinguished Service Award, 1993 (Box 17)
  - Luncheon for North Carolina Bishops and Judicatory Executives, 1993, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Outgoing Mail Log, 1989 Sep. 25 - 1992 Feb. 28 (Box 17)
  - Subject/Office Files, P-R, 1993, 7 folders (Box 17)
  - Racism/Racial Justice, 1988, 8 folders (Box 18)
  - Personnel Committee, 1988, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Peace and Security, 1988, 7 folders (Box 18)
  - Subject/Office Files, C-F, 1988, 29 folders (Box 18)
    Includes Finance Committee, 1988; Farmworker Ministry, 1988; Executive Board, 1988; Equal Rights Committee, 1988; Criminal Justice Committee, 1988; Christian Education Committee, 1988
  - Appointment Book, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Subject/Office Files, B-T, 1996, 54 folders (Box 18)
    Includes Farmworkers Ministry Committee; Executive Board; Equal Rights Committee; Criminal Justice Committee
  - Incoming letters to Collins Kilburn, 1993, 4 folders (Box 19)
  - Incoming letters to Collins Kilburn, 1996, 4 folders (Box 19)
  - North Carolina Workplace Reform Mission, 1995 (Box 19)
  - Workers Compensation, 1994 (Box 19)
  - Incoming letters to Collins Kilburn, 1994, 5 folders (Box 19)
  - Incoming letters to Collins Kilburn, 1997, 6 folders (Box 19)
  - 50th Anniversary, 1985, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Local Ecumenical Ministries, 1984-1989 (Box 19)
  - Farmworker Ministry Committee, 1978-1991, 13 folders (Box 19)
  - Committee for Equal Rights, 1978-1994, 5 folders (Box 20)
  - Farmworker Ministry committee, 1992-1994, 3 folders (Box 20)
  - Church and Public Education, 1985-1986 (Box 20)
  - Rural Life, 1990 (Box 20)
  - Criminal Justice Committee, 1978-1994, 8 folders (Box 20)
  - Christian Unity committee, 1977-1994, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Outgoing Mail Log, 1979-1980 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, 1980, 12 folders (Box 20)
  - Subject/Office Files, A-E, 1980-1981, 17 folders (Box 20)
    Includes Commission on Christian Social Ministries, 1980; ERA Committee and media packet, 1980-1981.
  - Subject/Office Files, C-H, 1980, 40 folders (Box 21)
    Includes ERA Committee, 1980; Committee on Christian Nurture, 1980; Criminal Justice Committee, 1980; Executive Board materials, 1980; Finance and Budget materials, 1980; House of Delegates material, 1980; and Hunger Committee; 1980.
  - NCCC Housing Development Corporation, 1983-1992, 51 folders (Box 21)
    Includes legal files.
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Attention: The legal materials in the Housing Development Corporation section of this box are sensitive. Patrons must sign a release form before use.
  - NCCC Housing Development Corporation, continued, 1982-1990, 21 folders (Box 22)
  - Incoming Incoming letters to Collins Kilburn, 1991-1993, 17 folders (Box 22)
  - Disaster response, 1988-1989 (Box 22)
  - Disaster response, continued, 1988 (Box 23)
  - Incoming letters to Collins Kilburn, 1988-1989, 6 folders (Box 23)
  - Caring Program for Children, 1988-1989, 9 folders (Box 23)
  - NCCC Housing Development Corporation, continued, 1983-1991, 16 folders (Box 23)
  - NCCC Housing Development Corporation, continued, 1992-1993, 4 folders (Box 24)
  - Correspondence and chronology files, 1990 (Box 24)
  - Appointment book, 1990 (Box 24)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1990, 4 folders (Box 24)
  - House of Delegates material, 1990, 7 folders (Box 24)
  - Money for TVTV, 1990 (Box 24)
  - NCCC Nominating Committee, 1990 (Box 24)
  - Triangle Regional Race Conference Planning Committee, 1990 (Box 24)
  - AIDS Ministry Task Force, 1990, 7 folders (Box 24)
  - Subject/Office files, C-E, 1989-1990
    - Christian Education, 1989 (Box 24)
    - Commission on Social Ministry on Christian Unity, 1990, 3 folders (Box 24)
    - Communications Committee, 1990 (Box 24)
    - Criminal Justice Committee, 1990, 13 folders (Box 24)
    - Equal Rights Committee, 1990, 3 folders (Box 24)
  - Subject/Office files, E-P, 1986-1990 (Box 25)
    Includes Equal Rights Committee, 1990; Farmworker Ministry, 1990; NCCC Housing Development Corporation, 1990; Interfaith Disaster Response Committee, 1986-1990; and Peace and Security Committee, 1990.
  - Correspondence and chronology file, 1981, 12 folders (Box 25)
  - Subject/Office files, A-E, 1981, 35 folders (Box 25)
    Includes Church Council Bulletin materials, 1981; Commission on Social Ministry on Christian Unity, 1981; Equal Rights Committee, 1981; and Executive Board materials, 1981.
  - Subject/Office files, F-G, 1981, 16 folders (Box 26)
    Includes Financial materials, 1981.
  - Committee Files (no longer existing), 1979-1999
    - Legislative Seminar, 1991-1993 (Box 26)
    - AIDS Task Force, 1990-1991 (Box 26)
    - Child and Family Advocacy, 1992-1990, 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Christian Education Committee, 1979-1988 (Box 26)
    - Denominational Staffpersons for Social Ministry, 1988-1989 (Box 26)
    - Economic Justice, 1983-1984 (Box 26)
    - Health Care Justice Force, 1992 (Box 26)
    - Peace and National Security, 1981-1993, 6 folders (Box 26)
    - Racism Committee, 1987-1995 (Box 26)
    - Interfaith Disaster Recovery, 1988-1990 (Box 26)
    - Housing Development Corporation, 1981-1994, 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Refugee Resettlement Committee, 1983-1985 (Box 26)
    - Tobacco Study Committee, 1983-1985 (Box 26)
  - General Files, 1995
    - A-Z Miscellaneous (Box 26)
    - Correspondence and Chronology files, 1995 January-1995 February, 5 folders (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, 1995 Mar.-Dec., 10 folders (Box 27)
  - Appointments, 1995 (Box 27)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1995 June (Box 27)
  - Outgoing Faxes, 1995, 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Audit, 1996 (Box 27)
  - House of Delegates, 1995, May 11, 3 folders (Box 27)
  - Nominating Committee, 1995 (Box 27)
  - Distinguished Service Award, 1995 (Box 27)
  - House of Delegates List, 1995, 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Subject/Office Files, J-R, 1995, 12 folders (Box 27)
    Includes Press Releases
  - Appointments, 1985 (Box 27)
  - Telephone Message Forms, 1985 (Box 27)
  - Subject Files, A-Z Misc., 1985 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, 1985 Jan.-May. (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, 1985 June-Dec., 7 folders (Box 28)
  - Arnie E. Brouwer, General Secretary National Council of Churches, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1985, 3 folders (Box 28)
  - 50th Anniversary Celebration, 1985, 9 folders (Box 28)
  - Governor - (Martin), 1985 (Box 28)
  - H-Misc., 1985 (Box 28)
  - House of Delegates, 1985, 4 folders (Box 28)
  - Nominating Committee, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Judicatory Heads Lunch, 1985, 3 folders (Box 28)
  - Religious Press Releases, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Legislative Seminar, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Secular Press Release, 1985 (Box 28)
  - N.C. Dept. of Corrections, 1985 (Box 28)
  - State Lottery, 1985 (Box 28)
  - N.C. General Assembly, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Report On N.C. Council of Churches, 1984 (Box 28)
  - Raleigh Report, 1985, 4 folders (Box 28)
  - Ex. Director Annual Report, 1985 (Box 28)
  - U.S. Congress, NC Delegation, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Committee Meetings, 1985
    - Christian Education (Box 28)
    - Christian Social Ministry (Box 28)
    - Christian Unity, 3 folders (Box 28)
    - Church and Public Education (Box 28)
    - Communications (Box 28)
    - Criminal Justice, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Equal Rights (Box 28)
    - Executive Board, 5 folders (Box 28)
    - Local Ecumenical Ministries, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Migrant Ministry (Box 28)
    - Peace and Security (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous, A-Z, 1996 (Box 28)
  - Correspondence, 1996 Jan.-Feb., 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Correspondence, 1996 Mar.-Dec., 12 folders (Box 29)
  - Appointments, 1996 (Box 29)
  - Children's Defense Fund Annual Conf., 1996 (Box 29)
  - Farewell Banquet for Jimmy Creech (Box 29)
  - Faxes, 1996, 3 folders (Box 29)
  - House of Delegates Meeting, 1996, 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Nominating Committee, 1996 (Box 29)
  - Distinguished Service Award, 1996 (Box 29)
  - Judicatory Heads, 1996, 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Press Releases, 1995-1996, 2 folders (Box 29)
  - NAEC Annual Meeting, 1996 (Box 29)
  - NCCC PR Piece, 1996-1997 (Box 29)
  - Presbyterians, 1996 (Box 29)
  - House of Delegates, 1981-1996, 10 folders (Box 29)
  - House of Delegates, 1979-1984, 6 folders (Box 30)
  - History, 1946, 1976-1995, 15 folders (Box 30)
  - Press Clippings
    - General America
      - Nuclear Weapons Freeze, 1981 (Box 30)
      - Central America, 1982 (Box 30)
    - Christian Unity, 1982 (Box 30)
    - Commission on Christian Social Ministries, 1982 (Box 30)
    - Councils of Churches, 1983, 1985 (Box 30)
    - Criminal Justice, 1970-1984 (Box 30)
    - ERA, 1977-1982 (Box 30)
    - House of Delegates, 1970-1984 (Box 30)
    - Hunger, 1973-1984 (Box 30)
    - Collins Kilburn, 1970-1986 (Box 30)
    - KKK, 1979-1980 (Box 30)
    - Legislative Seminar, 1977-1983 (Box 30)
    - Legislative Lobbying, 1974-1983 (Box 30)
  - Outgoing Mail Log, 1983 Sept. 9-1984 Aug. 27 (Box 31)
  - Appointments, 1986 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence, 1986, 13 folders (Box 31)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1986, 3 folders (Box 31)
  - Death Penalty Executions, 1986 (Box 31)
  - House of Delegates, 1986, 4 folders (Box 31)
  - Grants, 1986 (Box 31)
  - Housing Coalition, 1986 (Box 31)
  - Judicatory Lunch, 1986, 4 folders (Box 31)
  - Literature Ordered, 1986 (Box 31)
  - Press Releases, 1986 (Box 31)
  - N.C. General Assembly, 1986 (Box 31)
  - Raleigh Report, 1986 (Box 31)
  - South Africa Crisis, 1986 (Box 31)
  - Telephone Message Log, 1986 Feb. 10-Oct. 8 (Box 31)
  - Bishop Tutu Visit, 1986, 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Bishop Tutu Visit, 1986, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - U.S. Congress, 1986 (Box 32)
  - Endowment Fund, 1986 (Box 32)
  - 50th Anniversary Celebration, 1986 (Box 32)
  - House of Delegates Membership Lists, 1986, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Reports, Program ASC, 1986 (Box 32)
  - Appointments, 1987 (Box 32)
  - Misc. Alpha Files, 1987 (Box 32)
  - Correspondence, 1987, 12 folders (Box 32)
  - Church Council Bulletin, Misc., 1987 (Box 32)
  - Distinguished Service Award, 1987 (Box 32)
  - House of Delegates, 1987, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Nominating Committee, 1987 (Box 32)
  - Judicatory Lunch, 1987, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - George M. Kloster, Misc. Correspondence, 1987 (Box 32)
  - Legislative Seminar, 1987 Jan. 7, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - PR - Media, 1987, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - N.C. General Assembly, 1987 (Box 32)
  - Office Equipment, Xerox-2660, 1987 (Box 32)
  - Press Clippings (Box 33)
    - Evelyn Mattern, 1980, 1982, 1983 (Box 33)